# Frankfurt O. Ogunfunminiyi

**Telephone:** +234-7034-2724-65 **Email**: frankfurtmacmoses@gmail.com

## **Personal Summary**

A globally focused Information Technology expert with over 10 years' experience (in private and public sectors) centered around data, programming and decision making, with proven performance in delivering strategic results for corporate organizations.

Seeking a new and challenging position, that will make best use of my skills and experience in Data Analysis and Management.

#### **Formal Education**

Professional Certificates		
12. 1995 - 09. 2003	Bachelor of Agriculture in Soil Science, Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria	
Thesis Title	Improving Monitoring and Evaluation System Through Implementation of Big Data and Analytics In Osun State, Nigeria	
08. 2013 - 07. 2015	Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business School Netherlands	
Project Title	Comparative Analysis of Pig and Hive for Big Data Analysis	
	Technology, Ogbomosho	
01.2017 - 12.2017	Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Science, Ladoke Akintola University of	

Project Management Professional, PMP (ID: 1212004)
Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java EE 1.4 Platform
(SCWCD) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated
Sun Certified Programmer for Java Platform (1.4) (SCJP) Awarded by Sun
Microsystems Incorporated, Now Oracle Incorporation
Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) Awarded by Oracle Incorporation

# **Other Training**

# 2016 Coursera and John Hopkins University Bloomberg School of Public Health: Verified Certificate:

Data Science Toolbox
Getting and Cleaning Data
R Programming
Exploratory Data Analysis
Statistical Inference
Regression Model
Reproducible Research

## Coursera and University of California, San Diego , Verified Certificate:

2016	Introduction to Big Data Analytics
2017	Hadoop Platform and Application Framework
2016	Introduction to Big Data
2013	Monitoring and Evaluation for Results,IMA International, United Kingdom.
2013	World Bank Group's Impact Evaluation Training, Development Impact
	Evaluation Unit (DIME).
2015	Data Analysis, Statisitcal Computing and Report Generation, Big Team Resource
	Consultancy Services Limited, UI Workers' Cooporative Building, University of
	Ibadan.

## **Work Experience**

09. 2011 – present

### Bureau of Social Services, State Government of Osun, Nigeria

Head of Project, Program and Policy Evaluation / Management Information System

- Directly responsible for design, development and deployment of real time project monitoring software using Oracle Apex and Oracle 11g for strategic repositioning of Bureau of Social Services (BOSS) for effective monitoring and evaluation of government's projects; and to support effective budgeting by Ministry of Budget and Economic Planning.
- Prepared cost benefit analyses and scenario building based on data to assist in the signing of 10Megawatts solar farm between Osun State and GreenRG.
- Review proposals from service providers of application automation to government and scheduling products that ensure core business processes run faster, more accurately and without interruption.
- Partner with cross function agency to develop monitoring and evaluation procedure and framework for Osun State.
- Evaluate project processes and outcomes for the purpose of making recommendations and improvement.
- Create reports of output data on monthly basis, compiling information from all other units of a World Bank project titled "Youth Employment and Social Support Operations".

### 01. 2010 - 09. 2011

## ChamsSwitch Limited (a subsidiary of Chams Plc)

**Operations/Quality Assurance Manager** 

- Managed a 10-man team to develop web applications to extend the functionality of Base24 eps Switch.
- Designed and supervised the implementation of installation of Ivery web payment gateway 5 weeks before the deadline.

- Supervised step-by-step connection of many merchants to Ivery web payment gateway and bank - ATMs to Base24 Switch before the establishment of Nigeria Central Switch.
- Supervised the activities of junior staff including work allocation, training and conflict resolution.
- Responsible for managing activities of software developers for testing and integration of revenue collection application (Paycollect) to banking applications of head offices of 15 Nigeria Banks within 8 months.

#### 01. 2008 - 11. 2009

## SOFTWARE & RESEARCH VENDOR PROJECTS (MTN CONSULTANT)

**Project Coordinator/Senior Software Architect** 

- Worked with data warehouse team (taking a lead role as a consultant) in the revamping of MTN customer record database application from loading 20 million records per day to loading 90 million records per day without backlogs, using Perl scripts for sharing telecom tariff files into 14 directories and doing extraction, transformation and loading (ETL) of text files with oracle 9i PLSql and shell scripts on Sun Solaris Server.
- Lead a team of developer to develop an E-Ballot application for disposing used MTN assets to permanent staff using C# and DotNet framework.
- Worked directly with MTN project manager to create work breakdown structure for projects and activities scheduling using Microsoft Project software.
- Directly involved in bidding, negotiation, and securing the contract for development of vehicle tracking system and customer information management system for MTN Nigeria.

#### 04. 2006 - 10. 2007

#### NEW HORIZONS COMPUTER LIMITED

Developer / Project Co-coordinator and Instructor

- Team Leader, and Senior Instructor New Horizons / Babcock University joint program. Taught Object Oriented programming and SQLServer in Babcock University.
- Developed application on Microsoft Dot Net Platform: Test Engine for Students Performance Evaluation using Microsoft.Net 2.0 Platform with Microsoft SQLServer.
- Project Management Team and Co Developer for E-learning Application for Nigeria Bottling Company (NBC) and FCMB.
- Trained corporate organizations: Con-Oil Plc, Diamond, Bank First Bank Plc, EFCC etc - in JAVA, XML, VB.NET, SQL SERVER, PL/SQL and ASP.NET

References: To be provided on request.